不久前 在美国加州帕萨迪纳市的一间公寓里...
生活大爆炸
第194集 激动人心的首映式
在这紧张的时刻
我们的英雄 Leonard Sheldon Wolowitz和koothrappali知道
"新星球大战"电影首映式的票马上就要开始预售了
如果他们任务失败 没能抢到首映式的票的话
Sheldon发誓他们将永生不得安宁...
其他人相信他
- 嘿 已经开始卖票了!  - 什么?!
- Guys, tickets already went on sale!  - What?!
应该还没开始的啊
They're not supposed to be available yet.
我也不知道这是什么情况 但是真的已经开始卖了!
I don't know what to tell you, but they're on sale!
什么? 等下 你确定这是星球大战的票吗?
What? Wait. You're sure they're Star Wars tickets?
不是 这是"钢木兰花2: 更加坚强"的票("钢木兰花"是1989年美国电影)
No, it's Steel Magnolias 2: Even Steelier.
网站被挤爆了 我登不上去!
The web site's frozen. I can't get in!
- 是啊 我也是  - 我也一样!
- Yeah, me, too.  - Same here!
怎么办啊 要卖完了! 我们怎么办啊?!
Guys, they're gonna sell out! What are we gonna do?!
好吧 我下面要做的事与我一直所坚持的立场都不相符
All right, this goes against everything I stand for,
但我们现在也算是走投无路了
but desperate times call for desperate measures.
主啊...
Lord...
我是Sheldon Cooper
This is Sheldon Cooper.
你是我母亲的好朋友
You're good friends with my mom.
我知道我这辈子都在致力于否认你的存在
I know I've spent my life denying that you exist.
- 抢到了!  - 我会继续否认的!
- Got'em!  - And I will continue to do so!
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第11集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 网瘾少女凤梨酥
校对: UUUU吃吃吃吃
翻译: 凤梨酥 肉肉君 AU薇 無限月讀 波特妹子 舒大卷子
我真的很高兴你和Amy复合了
I'm really happy you and Amy are back together.
谢啦
Oh, thank you.
我也很高兴 不过我实在没法假装我是为你感到高兴
I'm also really happy, but I can't pretend it's for you.
离新的"星球大战"还有三天!
New Star Wars in three days!
再着急你也得等到周四
Hey, Thursday can't get here soon enough.
我要休几天假 一边吃完能撑死伍基人的"星球大战"麦片
I'm taking off work to watch the original trilogy
一边重温以前的星球大战原版三部曲
while I eat enough Star Wars cereal to choke a Wookiee.
呃 亲爱的 你应该知道周四是Amy的生日吧
Uh, sweetie, you do realize Thursday is Amy's birthday.
你也应该知道 我是在我们分手的那段时间里
And you do realize I bought my ticket
买的电影票吧?
when Amy and I were broken up?
希望你别再提这件事了
I hope you didn't need anything in that case,
因为我不会听的
because it's closed.
你们才刚刚和好
You guys just got back together.
你最好别连生日都不陪她过
You might not want to ditch her on her birthday.
我觉得Penny说的没错 你可以换一天去看电影
I think Penny has a point. You can see it another day.
可是我会被剧透电影的内容
But someone might spoil the movie.
但是对我来说Amy身上没什么可剧透的了
No one can spoil Amy's birthday for me.
天啊! 她又变老了一岁
Surprise! She's even older.
谁能猜得到?
Who saw that coming?
真是精辟
Oh, that's nice.
把这句话写在她的蛋糕上吧
Put that on her cake.
好吧 又是这套
Oh, great. This again.
Arthur 你怎么回来了?
Arthur, what brings you back?
呃 我也不知道 我... 我就是...
Uh, beats me. I... I just...
希望这不是个... 春梦就好
hope this isn't a... a sex dream.
以前 在我纠结的时候
In the past, you've come to me
你曾经来到过我身边
when I'm struggling with a dilemma.
还有... 一次... 你感到害怕的时候
And... and the one time where... where you were afraid,
我来当你的... 小夜灯
and you needed me for... for a night light.
这次... 有什么想不明白的?
What's... what's troubling you?
呃...
Well...
我的朋友跟我说
my friends are telling me
我应该陪我女朋友过生日
I shouldn't abandon my girlfriend on her birthday
而不应该自己去看"星球大战"的电影
to see the new Star Wars movie.
听起来没错啊
Well, sounds right.
我... 我能不穿这件...
Can... can I get out of this...
Muumuu了嘛? (夏威夷女性传统服装印花长袍)
Muumuu now?
这是绝地长袍啊
Those are the robes of the Jedi,
是银河系中和平与正义的维护者
the guardians of peace and justice in the galaxy.
而且... 他们... 他们还不穿内衣
And they... they... they don't wear underwear.
所以 你同意我朋友们
So, you agree with my friends
让我不去看首映的观点吗?
that I should skip the premiere?
嗯... 你... 你爱这个女孩吗?
Uh, do... do you love this girl?
爱
Yes.
但她知道星球大战对我来说有多重要
But she knows how important Star Wars is to me.
你应该让她知道...
Well, maybe you should show her how...
她对你有多重要
how important she is to you.
去看她想让我看的电影吗?
By seeing the movie she'd want me to see?
Sheldon 这电影你随时都能看
Sheldon, you can see this movie whenever you want.
但你能和这个女人在一起的时间
But you only have a limited number of days
却是有限的
that you-you can be with this woman.
和她在一起
Be with her.
没错
You're right.
好
Great.
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
我不知道 但希望是能穿内裤的地方
I don't know, but hopefully, somewhere I can wear pants.
Sheldon 怎么了?
Sheldon, what's wrong?
我想告诉你我准备和你一起过生日
I wanted to let you know I'll be spending your birthday with you.
好啊
Okay.
知道吗 我买了那天晚上星球大战的首映票
See, I... I had tickets to the Star Wars premiere that night,
但质子教授打扮成欧比旺·肯诺比
but Professor Proton came to me in a dream dressed as
进入我梦乡并说服我陪你
Obi-Wan Kenobi and convinced me I should be with you.
欧比...啥?
Obi... what?
你先去睡吧 晚安
I'll-I'll let you get back to sleep now. Good night.
嗯 晚安 等等
Okay. Good night. Wait.
嗯 Sheldon
Um, Sheldon,
你原来不想和我一起过生日啊?
were you actually not gonna spend my birthday with me?
太晚了 该挂了 晚安
It's late. Got to go. Bye.
Sheldon选择和
Good for Sheldon deciding
- Amy一起过生日很不错啊  - 当然
- to stay with Amy on her birthday.  - I know.
如果不和他一起看电影还是很奇怪
It's still gonna be weird to see the movie without him.
我们可以等几天一起去看
Well, we could wait a couple days and see it together.
你们好
Hello.
嘿 我们准备去漫画店了 你要一起来吗?
Hey. We're going to the comic book store. You want to come?
不 我不行
No, I can't.
我得为Amy的生日做准备
I need to make preparations for Amy's birthday.
所以我需要
Which leads me
做这件事
to the following bit of business.
这是我的星球大战电影票
This is my ticket to Star Wars.
我不需要告诉你它的实际价值
I don't have to tell you it is worth far more
要远高于他15.5刀的票面价值
than its face value of $15.50.
我希望你能把它送给对的人
I trust you'll give it to someone worthy.
没问题
You got it.
Penny可能和我们一起看
Well, Penny might want to join us.
这是我去看星球大战的电影票
This is my ticket to Star Wars.
Penny啊
Penny.
Penny啊?
Penny?
如果我说"请进"会怎么样?
What happens if I say, "Come in"?
试试看吧
Well, find out.
请进!
Come in!
Bernadette啊?
Bernadette?
Bernadette啊? Bernadette啊?
Bernadette? Bernadette?
请进!
Come in!
继续吧
Keep it up.
反正我也没地方去
I got nowhere else to be.
就直接进来吧
Just come in.
提醒一下 如果我想看贱女孩了
For future reference, if I want to watch Mean Girls,
我可以在Netflix在线看的
I'll stream it on Netflix.
不好意思 有事吗?
We're sorry. What do you need?
你们也知道
Well, as you know,
我将会和Amy一起庆祝她生日
I'll be celebrating Amy's birthday with her,
我想让你们帮我选一个
and I could use your assistance
最合适的生日礼物给她
in helping me select the perfect gift.
到目前为止
Sure. Well, so far,
我总共想出了三个点子
I've come up with three ideas.
第一是给她一个
The first is a chance for her
和洛杉矶爱乐乐团一起演奏竖琴的机会
to play the harp with the L.A. Philharmonic.
哇 这你都能安排?
Wow. You can really arrange that?
我说的是 一个机会 你懂得
Well, I said a chance, you know.
当你在本尼根餐厅
When you tell them it's your birthday
告诉他们今天是你生日的时候 他们对你简直关爱有加
at Bennigan's, they make a fuss.
我不觉得爱乐乐团会有什么不同
I don't see why the Philharmonic would be any different.
来点更实际点的怎么样?
How about something a little more realistic?
Amy喜欢自己织毛衣
Well, Amy enjoys knitting her own sweaters,
所以我想把费用全包 让她去
so I was thinking of getting her an all-expense-paid trip
参加威斯康辛的绵羊和羊毛节
to the Wisconsin Sheep and Wool Festival.
不好意思 我正等着你说逗你玩呢
Sorry. I was waiting for the bazinga.
等等 可能会很浪漫呀
Hold on. It could be romantic.
两个人远在天边
The two of them away together,
在飘雪的威斯康辛相拥取暖
keeping each other warm in snowy Wisconsin.
不不不 她会一个人去
No, no, no, no. She'd be going alone.
如果你觉得我很怕鸟的话
Well, if you think I'm afraid of birds,
你最好看看我在一群羊旁边是什么样子
you should see me around sheep.
好吧 选择三是什么?
Okay, well, what's the third option?
我和她上床
That I have coitus with her.
你觉得把Sheldon的票给Stuart怎么样?
What do you think about giving Sheldon's ticket to Stuart?
不知道
I don't know.
你之前和Stuart一起看过电影吗?
Have you ever seen a movie with Stuart before?
感觉就像和爷爷一起去看电影
It's like going with your grandpa.
他不吃爆米花
Instead of eating popcorn,
自己带了塑料盒装的鸡肉丁
he brings little pieces of chicken in Tupperware
和一保温瓶的热汤
and a thermos full of soup.
他没那么糟啦
He's not that bad.
嘿 Stuart 你周四晚上有安排吗?
Hey, Stuart, got any plans Thursday night?
呃... 我的医生很担心我的血液循环
My, uh... my doctor's worried about my circulation,
所以我打算在商场周围走一走
so I was thinking about walking around the mall.
为什么?
Why?
嘿 小伙伴们
Well... Hey, you guys.
记得穿双舒服的鞋
Oh, make sure to wear sensible shoes.
Wil 周四想去看星战吗?
Wil, want to go to Star Wars Thursday?
当然
Absolutely.
好的 带上Wil
Fine, take Wil.
看他会不会给你们带奶油蛤蜊汤
See if he brings you clam chowder.
好 好 好 好 好
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
让我们... 让我们... 梳理一下目前的选择
Let's... let's... let's just recap our options.
好吧 有弹竖琴 看绵羊...
All right, we've got harp thing, sheep thing...
还有一夜狂欢
Wild thang.
你们觉得她会喜欢哪一个?
Which do you think she'd prefer?
我查了一下绵羊和羊毛节的网站
Because I checked the Sheep and Wool Festival Web site,
现在只剩8000张票了
and there's only 8,000 tickets left.
Sheldon 和Amy亲近对你来说简直是巨人一跃啊
Sheldon, being physical with Amy is a huge step for you.
你准备好了吗?
Yeah, are you ready for this?
任何形式的亲密对我来说都是挑战
Intimacy in any form has been challenging for me,
但是我想告诉她她对我有多重要
but I'd like to show her how important she is,
感觉现在好像是正确的时机
and it feels like now might be the right time.
sheldon 你这么说好甜蜜
Sheldon, that's so beautiful.
那就这么定了
Then it's settled.
Amy的生日礼物将会是我的小丁丁
Amy's birthday present will be my genitals.
谢谢你们带我出来玩
Thanks for taking me out.
你生日要和Sheldon一起过嘛
Well, you're spending your birthday with Sheldon.
那我们就提前庆祝咯?
Why not celebrate early?
你想去哪?
So where do you want to go?
听说绿街上新开的墨西哥餐厅不错
I heard that new Mexican place on Green Street is good.
可以 或者我们带你去做个比基尼蜜蜡脱毛怎么样
Sure, sure. Or we could take you to get a bikini wax.
我为什么要在生日做比基尼蜜蜡脱毛?
Why would I get a bikini wax for my birthday?
呃 不知道 就是想到了
Uh, I don't know. It was just a thought.
我还是选墨西哥餐厅吧
I think I'll just stick to Mexican.
不错啊 也许在那之后 我们还能看个小黄片什么的
Great. And then maybe after, we can watch a dirty movie,
而且如果那谁有技术细节要咨询的话
and if anybody has any questions about what happened or how,
我们还能顺便解答一下
we can answer them.
好了 到底发生什么了?
Okay, what is going on?
呃 我们只想让你为明天可能的惊喜
Oh, we just want you to be prepared
提前有个心理准备
for any surprises that might happen tomorrow.
什么惊喜?
What surprises?
噢
Oh.
我们不想提前剧透什么
We don't want to spoil anything,
但是你看 Sheldon说他准备好啪啪啪了
but you should know that Sheldon said he's ready to be physical.
你胡扯呢吧!
You shut your damn mouth!
你们真听见他这么说了?
You actually heard him say this?
是的 他说他想做点什么
Yes. He said he wants to do something
来让你知道你对他有多重要
to show you how much you mean to him.
我... 难以置信 我...
I... I can't believe it. I...
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
我们真的为你高兴
Well, we're really happy for you,
我们知道他有多么在乎...
and we know how much he cares...
我知道该怎么办了! 去刮蜡吧!
I do know what to say! Let's get me waxed!
这儿怎么不是安吉·迪金森的卧室?
Why isn't it ever Angie Dickinson's bedroom?
安吉·迪金森是肯尼迪的情人之一
你回来了
You're back.
似乎... 似乎这个不取决于我
It... it doesn't seem like it's up to me.
我想你在这儿是因为...
I suppose you're here because...
我决定跟我女朋友身体接触了
I've decided to be physical with my girlfriend,
而以前从没这么干过
and I've never done that before.
等... 等一会儿
E... Excuse me for a moment.
反正试试也无妨
Well, it was worth a shot.
所以 你能帮帮我吗?
So, can you help me?
呃 好的 嗯...
Uh, all right. Um...
一旦... 一旦男的褪掉了
once... once the man gets
女人的...女人的小内内...
the... the woman out of her... out of her bloomers...
噢 不是那样的
Oh, no. Not that.
我... 我知道是怎么操作的
I... I understand the mechanics.
噢 好吧 好吧 因为 呃
Oh, good, good. 'Cause, uh,
我不知道现在的年轻人...
I have no idea what kids these days are...
是怎么叫...叫他们的那个的
calling their... their parts.
我想他们称之为"木耳"
I think they say “junk.”
这个世界究竟怎么了?
What is happening to this world?
你究竟想知道什么?
What... what do you actually need to know?
对我们来说 这是个重要的夜晚
This is an important night for us,
我担心自己会发蒙
and I'm worried I might be overwhelmed
然后把一切都搞砸
and ruin everything.
Sheldon 如果...如果你是和对的人一起
Sheldon, if... if you're with the right person,
那么... 不会有问题的
it... it'll be okay.
谢谢你 Arthur
Thank you, Arthur.
你是最有智慧的智者
You are the wisest of the wise.
呃 你能这么说... 真是个好人
Well, that's... that's very nice of you to say,
可是我觉得自己只是...
but I think I'm just an expression of...
你潜意识里的人物
of your unconscious mind.
噢 当然了 是的
Oh, sure. Yeah.
你看起来也很有意思
Well, you're fun to look at.
就是今晚了!
Tonight's the night!
是啊 终于等到今晚了!
Yeah, the wait is finally over!
我知道 你们终于要闭嘴了!
I know. Then you'll finally stop talking about it!
准备好了吗? 我们走吧
Ready to go? Let's do this.
快活点儿 你们!
Have fun, guys!
会的 不敢相信Sheldon居然不去
We will. I can't believe Sheldon gave this up.
就是啊
I know.
我们要比他爽多了
We're gonna have so much more fun than him.
不 他们不会的
No, they're not.
我了解他们 他们会的
Knowing them, they will.
还差15分钟开始!
T minus 15 minutes!
噢 你们知道Wil在哪吗?
Oh, did you hear from Wil?
他在路上了 检查一下要不要上厕所
Yeah, he's on his way. Time for bladder check.
不上
Check.
不上 慢着
Check. Wait.
管它呢 我要憋着
Screw it. I'm holding it.
大家都嘘什么呢?
What is everyone booing at?
嘿 伙计们 你们好吗?
Hey, guys. What's up?
嘿 Wil 你这是干嘛呢?
Um, hey, Wil. What you doin'?
我出演过星际迷航 支持主队而已
I was on Star Trek. I'm just rooting for the home team.
星际迷航大烂片!
Star Trek stinks!
哼! 生生不息 你奈我何!
Yeah? Live long and suck it!
寿星
Birthday girl.
寿星 寿星
Birthday girl. Birthday girl.
请进!
Come in!
嗷
Oh!
嗨 Sheldon
Hi, Sheldon.
嗨 抱歉我来晚了
Hello. Sorry I'm late.
我本来还给你买了个气球的
I also got you a balloon,
可惜它飘走了 我还追了一会
but it floated away, and I chased it for a while.
没事的 进来吧
That's okay. Come on in.
谢谢
Thank you.
呃 我... 我去找个瓶子装点水放花
Um, I'll... I'm gonna go put these in water.
好
Okay.
哦 今天感觉不太一样啊?
Ooh, this is different, hmm?
有蜡烛还有音乐
Candles and music.
你喜欢吗?
Do you like it?
有点诡异
It's kind of spooky.
我可以恢复原样的
I can change it back.
没事没事 你过生日嘛
No, no, no. It's your birthday.
只要没有戴着面具的怪人跳出来就没事
As long as no one jumps out in a hockey mask, I'll be fine.
那么...
So...
你今晚打算怎么过?
What'd you have in mind for tonight?
我想带你去吃一顿生日大餐
I thought I could take you out to a nice birthday dinner.
如果我们往东边走的话 说不定还能找到气球呢
If we pick a place east of here, we might find the balloon.
嗯 听起来不错 不过...
Um, that sounds nice, but...
我现在还不太饿
I'm not really hungry right now.
我觉得...
I thought maybe...
- 你可以先送我礼物  - 哦
- we could do presents first.  - Oh.
好吧
All right.
呃...
Um...
关于这个礼物 我有些话得告诉你
I should probably tell you something about this gift.
你是说 在你...
You mean before you...
把它给我之前?
give it to me?
是的
Yes.
在我把它给你之前...
May I ask you a question before I...
我能先问你个问题吗?
give it to you?
- 当然  - 我们为什么一直强调
- Of course.  - Why are we saying
"把它给你"?
"give it to you" like that?
呃 Sheldon
Sheldon,
我知道你的礼物是...
I know your present is...
今晚我们亲密一下
for us to be intimate tonight.
我知道了
I see.
这样可以吗?
Is that all right?
抱歉 不过现在人们都超爱打官司
I'm sorry, but this is a litigious society.
我还是需要你明确的口头同意
I'm gonna need verbal consent.
当然可以
Yes.
等一下 我上网找找有没有相关的合同可以签
You know what, let me pull a quick contract off the Internet.
好吧 要是你不喜欢"星球大战"的话 你为什么来这里?
So, if you don't like Star Wars, why are you here?
哦 我就是来看着玩玩
Oh, I'm just having fun.
所有人都把星球大战看的太认真了
Everyone takes Star Wars so seriously.
就好像这要是个烂片的话 他们这辈子都毁了似的
Like if the movie's bad, it's gonna ruin their lives.
是个烂片? 你听说了什么吗?
Is it bad? Did you hear something?
天啊 这电影不好看 你们谁杀了我吧
Oh, my God. It's bad. Somebody kill me.
看到了吧? 我就是这个意思
See? That's what I mean.
当你明早起来时 不管这是
When you wake up in the morning, whether this is
一部史上最好的电影还是超级烂片
the greatest movie ever or a total piece of crap,
你的生活完全不会因此改变
your life isn't gonna change at all.
他说得对
He's right.
是啊
Yeah.
不管发生什么
No matter what happens,
明天我们都会再回来看一遍
we're coming back tomorrow to watch it again.
你觉得Sheldon真的可以完成这件事吗?
Do you think Sheldon's actually gonna go through with it?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 他说他准备好了  - 是啊 但他还宣誓
- He said he's ready.  - Yeah, but he also swore
今年可以把南瓜的内瓤
this was the year he'd be able to pull the guts out
挖出来
of a pumpkin.
我觉得有戏 我们聊过
Well, I'm gonna stay positive. I mean, we talked.
我告诉他女人喜欢什么 他咯咯笑过后
I told him what women like, and after he stopped giggling,
神情还是很镇定的
he seemed pretty sure of himself.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
所以...
So, um...
我应该钻到被子下面和你一起吗?
should I get under the covers with you?
好的
All right.
- 你好  - 嗨!
- Hello.  - Hi!
你为什么在颤抖? 你冷吗?
Why are you shaking? Are you cold?
我只是... 真的很紧张
I'm just, um... really nervous.
紧张什么?
Why?
呃...
Well...
我等这天等了好久
I've been waiting for this for so long,
我只是... 在脑海中幻想了很久
I've just... built it up in my head.
我不知道会发生什么
I don't know what to expect.
我也是
Neither do I.
但是... 我们可以一起来发现
But... we can find out together.
好的
Okay.
我真的好紧张
I'm really nervous.
我知道
I know.
我们等这天等了好久
We've been waiting so long for this.
我们在脑海中想了好久
And we've built it up in our heads so much.
各位 这只是一部电影
Guys, it's just a movie.
是啊
That's true.
他说得对 这只是一部电影
He's right. It is.
不过 还记得加·加吗
Although, we all remember Jar Jar.
Leonard 我...又害怕了
Leonard, I... I'm scared again.
这比我想象的好多了
Well, I enjoyed that more than I thought I would.
我也是
Me, too.
我期待等你下次生日时我们再来一次
I look forward to your next birthday when we do it again.
我同意
That works for me.
这比我想象的好多了
I enjoyed that more than I thought I would.
我觉得我现在走不了路了
I don't think I can walk right now.
呃 Sheldon?
Uh, Sheldon?
Sheldon啊
Sheldon.
诶 Arthur
Arthur.
你在这干什么?
What are you doing here?
我... 我觉得
I... I don't think
我不需要什么建议了
I need any more advice.
我...我只是很好奇
I... I was just curious.
怎...怎么样?
How... How'd it go?
哦
Oh.
非常赞
It was amazing.
我... 我几天后去看了
I... I saw it a few days later.
多么赞的电影
What a movie.
但 呃... Amy怎么样?
But, uh, what... what about Amy?
哦 呃 她觉得还好
Oh. Uh, uh, she liked it fine.
但是她对这个系列没我这么有感情
But she doesn't have the history with the franchise I do.
好吧
Okay.
交谈... 愉快
Good... good talk.